This girl [snorts]
is tormented by demons every night
sleeping with her.
As we speak the whole family, all
members died. All of them.
And she says the last person who died
was the mother. And still from us, she
could call her and ask her, "You've
refused to inherit the altar." So it was
left with the sister of the mother who
now had to take her daughter to inherit
it. Now it is the daughter tormenting
this girl.
So when we began to pray with her, I now
receive anonymous texts.
Let me see if you can help her. Haha.
That is our vessel for producing
children in the world of darkness.
This girl is pregnant.
demonic
and if you test her, it's positive and
she loses it. That is a life.
So if you have a mother and a father,
even if they don't talk to you, you're
lucky.
There are children out here that were
adopted for wrong
reasons. We are still handling a case.
We had to move her from where she stays
close to us just to keep praying for
this girl.
The things we see in the office here
when people come
demon possessed ones. I was speaking to
one. She seated there. I'm seated here.
And she said, "I want to see you." So
she booked an appointment. She came. So
when she came, she she stopped at the
door of the office. Then she began
looking at at
the ceiling and then I asked what is
wrong. I said no you I cannot come close
to you.
I see fire. Then I knew this one is
demon possessed. So I said can I pray
for you? She said yes. Then after we had
prayed she gathered courage sat on the
seat. So I prayed again. Now tell me
what is wrong. Her mouth can't even
open.
They have held her mouth.
I pray for her again. Now speak, but she
can't look at me straight in the eye.
She's avoiding eye contact. But any
moment I ask her, why aren't you looking
at me? When she turns her her head to
look at me, I see a woman. When she
turns again and back to me, I see a man.
So I keep on seeing a woman. I keep on
seeing a man with some hairs like this.
So I said, "Hold on. I want to ask you a
question cuz you're going around. Are
you a lesbian?"
And the demon just manifested.
There's a Q&A session
and um very interactive
with lots of your contribution.
So be ready to share your Christian
experience. These are the moments we
sharpen each other. Ion sharpening.
No one claims monopoly of the word of
God.
Something you know which me I don't
know.
There's something I know which you don't
know. And that is the beauty of
fellowship.
Allow me with the first questions
that I've heard the one welcoming us the
coordinator saying. The questions were
sent
beforehand to them, not to me. To me,
I've just received them.
And uh
the spirit will lead us
through his word
through spirit of prophecy.
We are not debating.
Debates are not godly.
We are not competing.
Are you listening to me?
We are not debating. We are not arguing.
We are not competing.
We are sharing
what the Lord is telling us.
Not what you think is right, but
what the Lord would want us to to know.
The first question is an answer I would
like to get from parents
and I will just pick on anyone because I
know you have children this age asking
this question
and is a serious concern even that tone
sounds like we are serious.
Why don't parents want to accept
that we as their children are growing
up? What is your problem?
Why don't you just want to accept that
we are growing up and we would like to
meet and mingle
with people our age. This sounds like a
child who's been locked in the house
monitored.
The parent must be having
cameras everywhere.
Even when you take an Uber, they order
Uber for you. They monitor how it's
moving, whether you arrived or not.
Why don't parents want to accept that we
as their children are growing up and we
would like to meet and mingle with
people our age? They are often so hard
on us.
I think that is why you cannot find
wives and husbands. Now I know it's
because your parents are very hard on.
They don't even want you to mingle.
Yes. Parents.
Yes. Let me start with Baba Fidelis. Why
are you hard
on Fidelis?
You know Fidelis just moved the other
day to his own house after I made a lot
of noise. But the father is not happy.
What is wrong with you?
Thank you. That's a wonderful question
for us parents.
Number one, we are not hard
to allow our youths or our children to
mingle and meet with others.
>> We only want to control what we feel can
destroy them.
Otherwise if I am assured that stay
mingle and wherever they go they are
okay I will so be okay because
we mentor them to grow up as they grow
up we want them to be of their own but
as parents we have a responsibility to
train
teach and control so that they don't go
beyond control. Thank you.
>> H
still on you.
You want to be sure that where they are,
they are okay. How will you know where
they are, they are okay?
I mean, if Fidelis goes to meet a
girlfriend, do you want to be there?
>> No,
>> I don't want to be there.
I will
comfortably allow him to go
>> and will be comfort is doing boop b
[laughter]
is only them who feels that we are
controlling them so much.
>> Yes,
>> they are not trying to understand us as
they think we are not understanding
them. We always understand them.
>> So the problem is both children and
parents don't understand.
That that is what I get from Fidelis's
father. Parents don't understand their
children. Children don't understand
their parents.
Where is the problem? What is this
you're calling control? And to what age
would you still want to control?
To what age?
Me I see marriageable people here
particularly the ladies all of them are
marriageable. Maybe the men are headed
somewhere, but the ladies marriageable.
What? What?
What?
20.
To what age do you still want to control
these children? Aren't you confident
that they can be independent out there?
Yes, Elder Mukai.
Yes,
you you don't have a problem.
The question they are complaining, why
don't you just trust that they okay? Why
don't you want them to mingle?
>> You know, they have not demonstrated
that they can be trusted.
>> I tell you,
>> they need
>> Yeah. You have not demonstrated that you
can be trusted.
>> And I've always said that the parents
are always thinking about the safety
>> and the wellbeing of their children.
>> Not allowing you to go and mingle out
there
>> especially when you have not
demonstrated that you can stand on your
feet
>> gives a lot of anxiety to the parents.
But myself
at the moment there's no child who lives
with me.
>> I know
>> when they want to go I let them go.
>> Sometimes
you feel concerned but you think that
when they left to go
>> they may learn to be on their own
>> and therefore
they get to a point where you can
release them wherever they want to go.
Whether they going to UK, whether they
going to Australia,
>> you are sure that they able to stand on
their feet.
>> But the moment they don't demonstrate
they can stand on their feet, they are
great.
>> There's got to be some control.
>> I I agree with with that. I agree with
with that.
Yes. Give it to Mama Bismak. See how she
controls Bismar. [laughter]
>> Where is Bismak,
>> pastor? So you separated.
>> Ah, good. Good, good, good.
[laughter]
>> Uh, pastor, I wish I could give you the
background to my sitting next to him in
the morning. Yes.
>> But, uh, because you were
>> No hard feelings. No hard feelings. Even
>> I know you were controlling him
[laughter]
>> even even on my part. No hard feelings.
Uh so I just want to tell the young
people that uh from my own experience
growing up as a child of someone as well
as from my experience parenting
there is not a single person in this
world interested in your success as much
as your parents. That's a given. You can
take it to the bank. We want you to be
successful in every way in your career
in your social life to get to your um
your own family and to grow it for the
kingdom of God. Now the person has asked
a very interesting question because I
think it comes from out of the
experience with the parents
>> and I believe parents have got varied
experiences here
>> and uh a child such as that who is
experiencing that I totally agree with
Elder
>> Mukaya
>> uh you need to make your parent trust
you
>> know that if I am allowing since we are
using bism if I am allowing bism to go
out that he will be responsible enough
to make decisions that are going to be
for his own welfare, his own security,
his own safety and he will come back uh
uh to the house hall. Uh Bismar is my
second child and they all know I mean
none of my children live with me in the
house now and I've always told them you
can go wherever you want
>> uh anywhere you want in this world as
long as you ask yourself this question
if Jesus found me there
if he found me there
>> what would be my fate would be very
happy with me and celebrate me will he
be very disappointed in the place where
I am in I I think for me that's the
standard that has always operated in my
in my in my house.
>> And so young people please make your
parents comfortable.
Make them trust you to such a level that
when you say I am going to meet uh
Bismar they say okay fine bism is going
to meet bismar and she will come back
fine uh back at home. If you don't
parents are very anxious we are anxious.
We are living in a society that has got
a lot of insecurity. A society that uh
there are now many things moving around
and so we become controlling not because
we want to but because we care about
your welfare, your success and how
you're presenting yourself. So I think
the simple answer is that both parents
and children and and the child or
whoever has asked we need to work on
that uh trust level. You need to make
your parents trust you and parents you
need to know that or we need to know
including me that life is a curve.
People are born
>> they grow we take them to school they
grow maybe they start careers uh and
they start uh uh uh maybe families etc.
And with every stage in growth we need
to release. We need to release. We need
to release. Give autonomy give
responsibility facilitating decision
making and kind of like step back so
that you can be consulted. Otherwise if
you are too tight these children will
never tell you anything.
>> Now to give the background as a matter
of fact it's Bismar who asked me to come
and sit next to him. Pastor I was seated
very far away.
He said he he sent a deacon. He sent a
deacon and said, "Please go and ask my
mom to come and sit."
>> There's a girl disturbing me. H
>> I don't know. [laughter]
Let me have a response from our young
people.
What is your feeling as a young person?
Do you think you're responsible enough?
Do you think you can be trusted?
Yes,
this is okay. Please do. Please do.
Pass the mic to the other side.
Sound.
Happy Sabbath.
>> Happy day.
>> Happy Sabbath.
>> Uh, my name is Lynette. I'm actually a
guest here.
>> Okay,
>> no worry.
>> Yeah. Um, I think my what I was thinking
about, especially as I'm listening to
their parents talk here, I was thinking
about how I I like that we're talking
about how everything that we are doing
is for our kids' welfare. That that is
the basis point. We all agree on that
that we want our kids to to succeed and
be and be okay. But it can also come to
a point where that care can turn into
fear and then it we can act out of that
fear and that's when someone is saying
that their parent is being too hard on
them you are actually harming that child
in some way especially socially because
we all need to grow in all spheres of
life. We need to grow spiritually,
mentally, emotionally and socially for
one to succeed and to thrive as a human
being. you need to grow socially and
when that aspect of ourselves is denied
us then it means we are lacking
something and we fail at something and
um I think I also have a question when
you're talking about how we need to show
our parents that we can be trusted what
does that actually mean like I think you
need to let me go out you tell me a cu
time I come back during that time and
you're like okay I can trust you so if I
don't go out you don't try trial and
>> you just imagine I cannot be trusted
>> exactly
>> and you've not even allowed me to go
out.
>> Exactly. Then it's not a functional
relationship. Yeah.
>> Yes. There's a young person there.
Yes.
I think it's a nice disc. I have eight
questions.
I've seen one that requires a whole week
to answer.
>> Check. Okay. Happy Sabbath.
>> Happy day.
>> Okay. That's a very interesting
question. Uh, okay. Sometimes I feel
it's not a matter of trust issues. It's
a matter of um cultivated tendencies to
evil. You see, there are things that our
parents were doing in their past. So,
they have a fear.
[laughter] Ha.
[screaming]
Yeah.
Let me tell you. Let me tell you. Well,
let me tell you. When you are when you
are a husband and wifeh, which you're
about to be, and you have a spouse who
is adulterous, they always want to think
what they do out there is what you're
also going.
[laughter]
Yeah. So, uh, at the end of the day,
it's just that fear, you know, I I used
to smoke bang. So, if I allow him to go,
he's going to do the same thing, I tell
you.
>> So, sometimes it's not even all about
trust issues. It's all about them. Mhm.
Mhm.
>> And the fact that And the fact uh and
the fact also that at some point you
can't quite reason with them
>> cuz they they kind of feel infalluable,
you know, like some kind of a god.
>> They always right.
>> Yeah. I'm here to speak. You're here to
listen. Yeah.
that [laughter] that that young man has
a very strong point. At times the fear
comes from the life we have led and we
would want to project it on our
children. I saw some hand.
Okay, let's finish from the side.
>> Um, okay. So, I I agree with my brother
over there, but then the I wanted to
counter the lady who said about being uh
allowed to just go out. Uh, I think we
need to understand um anytime there's
something happening, you have to look at
all the dimensions.
So in my argument I'd say some of these
parents are being protective. Yes, there
are those who have uh such kind of
issues but I would say a majority of
these parents are just very protective
because like the elder said you they
don't know what these kids are going to
to to do there. So my sister when you
say let your parents just let you go out
and then give me cafe where are you
going exactly? You want to go you're not
reporting where you're going. you just
want to that freedom I don't think it
can really exist and maybe if I may give
an analogy of course I'm a man um and
maybe ladies have found themselves in
this kind of situations where you are in
a relationship relationship with
somebody who wants you to be updating
them on where you're going and some of
these healthy relationships have been
viewed as toxic just because your
boyfriend is asking you where are you
going you know what are you going to do
who are you going with so there is that
aspect of being a protective boyfriend
and I I think that's the same thing
that's happened. I mean, it happens to
the parents as well.
>> They're just being protective. We just
want to know where are you going? You
know, what what time will you come back?
So, if also you have a bad history as a
child, if maybe there's a moment your
parent caught you doing something, maybe
you came back to the house uh tipsy or
something, then be rest assured uh
they'll just that that that freedom will
the sense of freedom will just come to
an end. M I love the way you're talking
as a as as a boyfriend and as a parent.
[laughter]
>> Yes, I'm a boyfriend.
>> I love the way you you you're talking.
There's nothing wrong in being
protective, but at times we can be
overly protective. And that is what she
said. It now turns now to be fear. Okay.
Of course, I expect when you leave my
house, tell me where you're going, who
you are meeting, what time you will be
back. Okay? And if you think you will
stay longer, give me a call. Tell me I
am staying longer because of 1 2 3.
And if it doesn't make sense, please
show up in my house.
Why? It is my house.
There's a life at times our young people
want to live that can only be
lived by someone who is in their what?
House. So it is simple. If you want to
leave it, you just go to your what? To
your house. But when you're under my
care, I think I need to know where
you're going, who you're meeting to do
what, when are you coming back, and if
you stay longer, let me know why you're
staying longer or what has delayed you.
So, I think being protective is not
wrong,
especially in the world that we live
today, but do not be over
protective.
There was someone else on that side.
Yes. still listening to our young people
>> and all the time
>> the Lord is good. I'll read from the
book of Proverbs chapter 22 and verse 6.
The Bible reads, "Train up a child in
the way he should go and when he is old,
>> he will not depart from it."
>> So parents, if you've brought me up in
the best way possible, why are you
worried?
>> Huh?
If you have done your beath
why are you worried
it means you're worried because you did
not do your
[laughter]
You only worry if you didn't do your
what? Your part. Cuz you know too well
this one I have raised. I've not taught
them to be independent. Okay. Yes. I
have not taught them that this is how
you make decisions. So now they want to
go and you know too well they can
because you didn't teach. So you worried
Mia train up a child in the way you
should do what? Hey so that you don't
worry when now they want to see their
boyfriend
and girlfriends. Anybody there?
Yes.
>> Happy Sabbath.
>> Happy day.
>> Growing up we used to be told of
Galatians.
>> You mean growing up?
>> I'm still growing up.
>> How old are you? [laughter]
Okay.
You understand?
>> You You're still growing?
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Now, growing up from 206. Yes.
>> Okay. Uh we were being told of Galatians
6:1. But children obey your parents and
you know you know it that your days
maybe and so on and so on.
parents do not provoke not offend
>> your children. So I I agree you we agree
that parents you really want the best
for us that we agree and then even
looking back there are things that I
didn't agree with my my parents then but
now I see that it was in my best
interest
>> but again can we have a conversation
>> can you [clears throat] be able to help
me understand why you are doing this not
to talk at me not to give instruction at
me I feel like there's a way in which
parents want to be like uh you are there
to take instruction around
and again the last thing I want to say
is um
>> continually
continually we in the technology world
we are updating software during due to
changes security TCT but parents want to
use the software they used growing up
You know, [laughter]
you know, we complain about the genes,
this, that.
>> They refuse to update themselves.
>> We need to update your software, please.
>> Hey,
okay.
Okay, there's one more hand there. Yes,
there's a hand there. There's one here.
Okay, before we get the final one from
our parents. Oh, the elder is also
there.
>> Oh, happy Sabbath.
>> Happy day.
Okay. I thank uh everyone who has
communicated about the issue and
actually I'm going to tackle some areas
in three perspectives.
>> Yes. one
there's a difference within uh with
communication and having a conversation
and uh our parents I'm not saying all
but some of them instead of having a
conversation with us their children they
are having communication
>> one way
>> one way communication okay
>> so I think uh if we uh if our parents
can have a conversation with us.
>> And the second thing is trustworthy.
>> The third thing
is
um let me
I think uh how how how are you going to
handle me? You know some parents can can
take you like they are commanding you
know they telling you do this
>> even you you personally you are saying
this thing is not the right thing.
>> But because he or she is your parent you
have to agree and though your heart is
not well conversant with you.
>> Thank you.
>> Look at you
conversations
you stop ordering us around. Yeah. that
which you want to be done, you can say
it in another way. We will still do it.
You don't have to shout.
Yes, you don't have to command. You just
request politely.
So, if you can just do
I would like to leave with a car. It's
dirty. Just uh give it a quick cleaning.
Is the same thing we want but say in
different different tones. It's
conversations. We understand each each
other. There was one more hand here.
Yes, baby girl.
Um I was just adding on to what my
brother said. Um he was saying about um
the times changing and I was just saying
that nowadays social life is a bit more
expensive because now people do not um
you don't neighborhood friends because
you most probably don't even know your
neighbor. about the friends you have,
you must plan a meeting to go and have a
socialization.
>> Where your friends are where
>> I mean if you have
>> they're not in the neighborhood.
>> Yes.
>> So probably you met in campus.
>> I'm a nation. You don't know.
>> So yes, you probably met in primary or
in high school. Yes.
>> And so those are the friends you're
tight with. And so when you want to meet
you like
it's not like you can go away from home
>> still you can just meet around the
neighborhood and hang out.
>> So then that permission aspect that has
to be locked into
>> so your parents want when you meet you
meet in the house
>> or around the neighborhood there's no
money involved
nowadays
>> who who should be funding those social
meetings
>> your parents. [snorts] Ah,
okay. You you should be funding a
meeting in Java. Okay.
You should there's there's a parent
there's a parent and I know she would
not be offended if I share this. There's
a parent that lost her daughter
uh to date. She still
hasn't accepted completely. She feels
she would have done better.
Okay. Uh there's there's money that this
girl needed
to go and use it for something
and I think she said what you need it
for right now
uh probably you'll need it later not
now. Okay. So she left like someone who
the way you just leave the house up to
late in the night she had not come
kumbbe a friend had called her to a club
and uh as she was leaving
waiting for
a cab.
A drunk driver was also leaving the club
when negotiating the corner, hit her
and she was in the trench
and uh the boyfriend simply came took
her to his place
thought it was just you know she'll be
back to normal.
Then when he realized it's getting
worse, called the mother. By the time
they get to hospital, she was dead.
She hasn't accepted that death even
today. She says, "Maybe I should have
given her the money she
wanted.
She would have used it to come back home
or something." People get stranded, is
it? Yes.
She's still regretting that that bit. I
tell her just let it go. Uh all the
answers we will get in heaven
for now. It has gone. You have buried
and uh don't blame you yourself.
I think with all sincerity,
if my daughter wants to meet some
friends
in Java, the truth is she's not working.
Eh,
yeah. Tell me early enough,
I would want to meet some friends in
Java. Even if it's another friend
funding, it is only good your daughter
also has what?
Some money.
Some money. It's important. Even those
of us that date when a boyfriend calls
you.
Don't be in the habit of going to a
restaurant without money
in your pocket. Just tell your dad, "I'm
meeting my boyfriend, but I cannot go
without what?
Hey boyfriend,
I told you
just like someone has said there's our
age. Our age, a man will come around
home.
It's only you who knows where he's going
because you know him, passes along the
fence, comes back. He's It's only you
who know this is Mooro and wants to see
me. Today they don't do those kinds of
things. Today they say let's meet uh
TRM. No. Yeah. But you need as a child
to be open enough to let your parent
know what are you going to do in TRM?
Who are you meeting? Okay. So that I
give you money and I know you're safe.
If anything happens, you can always find
your way your way home. That was on a
very quick note. There are some parents
here that wanted to speak. Yes. Yes.
Yes, Baba.
Okay. Um, I just wanted to address
what? Unpack.
>> They're saying they want to see your
face.
>> Unpack the mistress
>> to see if you are serious.
Oh, yeah.
She has a grandchild. So, you allow her
just sit. Okay. Yeah.
Okay. Um, happy Sabbath.
>> Happy day.
I just wanted to address or unpack the
mistrust
and part of it has been said by pastor
>> but uh the fact is that sometimes
and over here I want to agree first of
all with what Munyangi said and what
they like I want to align as align
myself to that
>> and then say that um depending on the
age and I believe that we are dealing
with maybe collegegoing youth
and working youth. I want to address
those ones. Even with those ones, the
mistress comes in this manner.
You tell me you're going to hang out
with ABC,
I allow you, you go as a parent, as a
mother, you know, but then later on I
discover you XY Z.
>> It wasn't ABC.
>> So they lied.
>> They lied.
It is also true that some of our
children have actually ended up in death
>> because they did not completely be
honest with their parents
>> as to their whereabouts and they have
been found in such places like you named
for example clubs.
Stuff has happened in that club.
bites have erupted and children have
been killed
and that gives us shivers when you tell
us that you're going to be with Mary and
then I come to discover that you were
with totally different people that I do
not even know we do not even
>> so you cannot be trusted
>> you so you can't be trusted so I have
trained you well it's not always true
that we do not train you
>> we may have done our part but in the
process you picked some habits
which I do not know about.
>> Not picked. You want to become
adventurous.
>> Oh, okay. You want to become
>> You're just a good girl. But there are
some girls who have influenced you
towards some adventure that you know too
well my mother will not accept.
>> Exactly. So I have to lie about sorry
pastor.
>> Yes.
>> So that she said the word influence.
You have gone to be with people that we
do not associate with that we do not
know that I will not expect you to be
hanging out with. And for the reason
that you know that I will not accept
that you lie to me. That's how the
mistress comes.
>> Thank you. I think one more last person
my elder is there. Okay. And then pastor
oh three people elder just give to the
elder there first as we come like this
and then we find a middle ground.
>> Yeah. Thank you. Uh thank you pastor and
thank you our youth. It's very good that
you are open
and pointing to our weaknesses.
>> Um, let me assure our youth, there is no
parent who is perfect.
There's none who is perfect.
And sometimes some youth look at other
parents, they think they are better than
their own.
Pastor I work in a hospital
and um one time
a young man came to hospital with
jaundice.
Jaundice is yellowess of eyes
and he was very sick.
So we investigated we found that he had
alcoholic liver failure.
The person who brought this young man to
hospital is a friend.
But because you know they didn't have
money to pay to pay
that they called their mother.
The friend called the mother and said so
and so is sick and I brought him to
hospital.
This young man had lost his father
through a road accident. So this was a
single parent.
When the mother comes, I find that it is
a fellow church member.
She actually didn't know that her son
whom she has trained in in in the in the
church takes alcohol to a level
that he has developed alcoholic liver
failure.
You talk of trust,
the mother trusted the son very well.
And he used to even give him money when
he says I'm going out mom please give me
money.
In Kenyata hospital second floor there
is the youth and adolescent center.
Why was it created?
It's because so many youth have got so
many problems which are associated with
the drug intake and even HIV
such that it was an epidemic and the
hospital had to create that center and
it is for free. You go there as a youth
and you are handled free
our children. It is not that we don't
love you.
It is not that we don't trust you.
As Elder Mukaya said, you have to prove
that you can be trusted.
You have to prove.
If I realize that your company is
probably what I don't like,
I will tell you no.
So please, why do we have so many young
people in problems of drug intake?
such that a a hospital which is not even
related to any Christian institution has
to create a center for the youth.
Uh pastor I was not answering any
question. I was throwing some spanner in
the works.
>> Mama Mary wants to complicate the the
question. She she wants something
explained.
Let her ask as my elder and my mother
and pastor
answer that question. Now complicate the
question for us.
>> Yeah. Um we were accused of uh using our
background.
>> I'm a go slow now. using [laughter]
using a background and not being um up
to date with the times.
>> Yes.
>> And I agree. I grew up my grandmother
told me um there's no self in the
darkness
>> and I I took that as gospel truth. What
I've [snorts] never understood is
why should the party always start after
seven? Why should always be in the Now
we are going for dinner.
>> Why? Why? We We have a whole
>> Mama Mary dinner is not in the morning.
>> Sunday. We have a whole Look, we have a
whole Sunday is from 6:00 a.m. to 6:00
p.m. Why should we start at 9:30 in the
night? I need my sleep. Why is this
thing Why we going to town? 9:00 is when
the thing is starting ending when
streets are not even safe. Tell me which
mother will not worry about it.
>> Yes. Yes. If it is not dinner,
>> if not if it's not dinner and then this
>> and then this choice of eating things we
didn't teach you to eat, drinking things
didn't to drink, where do we go wrong?
You know dinner is the main meal of the
day.
>> Sure.
>> It is not necessarily the last one. The
last one is the supper. Okay. So dinner
is not necessarily in the night.
>> Anyway, that is a by the way. Now
>> 10 dinner 7 [laughter]
>> now
um you know there is no standard uh
formula
>> and I think throughout the week right
from Sunday
>> yes
>> uh there have been nuggets here and
there
but uh I guess uh
we lost it both sides when we started
chasing
the red herring
and uh here is uh what I see
when uh the blueprint was broken.
Okay.
And when it was broken, we were sold
something else. My daughter Natalie will
say when it was being broken, we were
given
the face value of that which was
replacing it. The ex
exoteric
meaning
>> of the new proprint that we are picking
up.
>> The esoteric me meaning she used that
exact word. We we were not diligent
enough
>> to go and dig and understand. If we had
gone to consider the esoteric meaning of
the blueprint we were getting,
>> we would have been a in a better place
to understand. In other words, even at
the individual level,
if
you are able to look what is behind
because the exo exoteric meaning is
fantastic,
>> very nice.
>> In fact, you buy it once,
>> but the [snorts] hidden meaning,
esoteric,
it calls for a diligent
mind to go into it. look at it, dig the
things and then make decisions and think
this is where we are actually
missing it a lot. Even uh our children,
my children are here by the way.
>> Um they will come up with something
and we
>> The other one is laughingly
quickly. We will kick quickly fight
without
even saying come let us reason together.
>> Thank you.
>> Mine was a comment.
>> Yeah. So what you sell us are the
externalities
the real motive we have no idea.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Maybe what I wanted to say have
been said
>> but I think this is the right place
where to say something.
Um you know the question was very nice
um
I remember
I I went to college when I was old
so I was with the young people
and then there was an incident that
happened
a very innocent man who in church
was in in fighting in fighting
in fight to go for they say what is it a
party or something like that
>> but but the young men
uh had their own plans.
So when
they were drinking whatever they were
drinking, this guy was very noent.
But when he went out
so unknowingly
she did what?
He drunk
where she was
police.
So
uh I asked one of we used to go for
let's say evangelism
boys and girls.
So I had a privilege to ask one of them
two girls.
What do you think has made
It is because our parents
never prepared us
>> for what is ahead of us
and and that's why our the parents here
are trying to say that whatever they try
to to do is for your own
safety.
So I asked what do you want us what do
you want your parents to do then or you
know I was also a parent what do you
want me to
to do say
have a conversation with us
>> just don't tell me don't go out without
telling me
>> what's there
You know, you can tell don't go to the
bar or something like that.
The child must wants to know why
because you can be very innocent
people for you.
And you know
zero.
>> Am I trying to say something?
>> Yes. Yes.
>> So
it's good that we are here today.
>> Parents who are here
prepare our children for what's outside.
What about the time when I now out? I'm
no longer next to you.
[snorts]
I'm doing whatever I want to do.
So parents take
be very careful what you are saying. Let
it be a lesson.
The way you are brought up and the way I
was brought up see
is not. It is not. So it is time for us.
But it is you
HIV.
What will be?
>> Thank you, pastor. You want to speak
before we close this chapter? cuz I know
there's a concert at 4.
>> It's already 4:00.
>> Yes, it's already 4. But I'll just add
uh from uh the book Advent the Adventist
home chapter 75 that says uh parental
guidance on social affairs. So there's a
paragraph here that says um paragraph 3
of page 466 that says let the youth be
placed in the most favorable
circumstances possible for the company
they keep the principles they adopt the
habits they form
will settle the question of their
usefulness here and of their future
eternal uh interests with a certainty
that is infallible. So uh I think this
chapter has so much uh like even uh on
how to build trust on uh even evening
debts actually it speaks about it
>> and
>> evening debts
>> dates
uh
>> or dates.
>> Yeah. It says uh
>> yes okay it speaks about where are the
evening spent. Yeah. So uh so every son
and daughter should be called to account
if absent from home at night.
>> Parents should know what company their
children are are in and at whose house
they spend their evenings.
>> Some children's uh some children deceive
their parents with falsehoods to to
avoid exposure of their long of their
own course. Yes. So I think it's a very
good topic. Uh our parents and fellow
youths can be able to have the pleasure
of studying it more. Chapter 75 of the
book Adventist home.
>> Thank you. You go study 75. Oh, these
are our guests or what? See some
commotion out here. Looks like they are
those who have come for music only
now.
Mama. Okay. Yes, mama.
I would like to read something that I
read somewhere and I put it in my book
before I give my one comment.
This is a conversation between a
grandson and a grandfather.
One day a little boy asked his
grandfather, "Grandpa,
how did you live back then
without technology, without phones,
without televisions, without computers,
without game consoles, without
refrigerators,
air conditioners, so fast internet,
without cars?"
And the grandfather
answered,
"Just like you live now
without respect,
without proper manners,
without genuine education, with poor
character,
bad temper,
lacking a heart of kindness, without
shame, without humility, and without
honesty. We who lived in the 1930s
to 2000s
were a fortunate generation.
Our lives were living proof of
happiness. We played with real friends,
not with virtual ones online.
When we rode bicycles, we never wore
helmets. After school, we did our
homework on our own and helped our
families with chores.
If we felt thirsty, we would drink from
fountains, waterfalls, or tap water, not
bottled water. We never worried about
getting sick, even when sharing a cup
with friends. We never got fat from
eating potatoes and sweet potatoes every
day. Even if we walked barefoot, our
feet were fine. Although our parents
weren't wealthy, they gave us love
instead of material gifts.
We never had mobile phones, no DVDs,
no PSPS game consoles
and all that.
But we had real friends.
We went to friends houses without
invitations,
simply sharing the food we had. Our
parents lived nearby,
and we often spent joyful times
together.
We might have only black and white
photos, but in those photos,
you can see our colorful memories. We
were unique. We were the happiest
generation
for I would like you to listen to this
last sentence. For we were the last
generation to obey our parents
and the first to listen to our children.
We are a limited edition.
Learn from us. So I don't know what kind
of h freedom our young people want.
I don't know why they are complaining.
They do not want to listen to us.
We may be old.
We may look like we are old school,
analog, whatever you can call us
anything. But we treasure
wisdom and that is what we want to give
you. We have already answered the
question. The answer is for me children
be friends to your parents and parents
develop that friendship.
There's nothing I don't talk about with
my children from the time they were
young and like my sister
Rosumba there if my child asked me
something
and I knew that they are going to the
wrong place and you know your children
this one is hotteered this one would not
listen whatsoever you do I would tell
them ask yourself
what would Jesus do in in a situation
like this.
I'm glad that young man who gave us the
question said
they are growing
just like a little baby when they start
to stand or to start taking their first
step. I am there worried to hold them
and pick them up when they fall. Even
the psalmist in Psalms 23, the shepherd
has a staff and a rod. What are they
for?
That crooked stick is to get that sheep
>> before the ship falls over the cliff.
Trust is and and it is and when you
become honest even from the little
little things at home
>> and parents love you. We want the best
for you
>> and we will give you time to go out.
Make your choices. We have already told
you they have consequences.
So I'm your friend. You're my friend.
Let's have a talk.
>> Thank you.
It's a nice one.
>> In economics, those who do economics,
there is something they call set paribas
to mean all factors held.
So I want us to assume that we are
holding all factors
constant cuz you can tell there are many
factors that cause whatever our young
people are worried about. But assuming
now all factors are held constant.
You agree with me?
Parenting today
is different from parenting our time.
For you to raise a child.
What is that verse you read us? Amanda.
Yes. Train up a what? Ellen White asked,
"Before you train, do you even know the
way that child should go in the first
place? Before you even start training,
do you know the way that child should
go?" I believe three things are required
from a parent, which I think it was
possible with our parents, but I don't
see it possible with today's parents. I
mentioned them here. It requires
availability.
Parents today are not available.
Am I lying?
Our children
are growing like plants.
Children are not plants to grow.
Children are raised
And availability is important.
I guess it's because back then daddy
would go to work, mommy would remain
where? At home to raise the child.
I believe so.
Today both parents are missing in action
from the third month after they have
finished maternity leave. Those of us
that are lucky would add our annual
leaves up to 6 months. Beyond there, the
mother is conspicuously
absent.
And we have delegated the raising of our
children to our households strange
hands.
who should cook, do laundry, take care
of your things in the house, bath
children, do one, two, three. They're
not raising those children. They're only
giving food and bathing the child. So,
our children are just growing by chance.
That is the language I would use. There
is no one to instruct. And let me tell
you, when we don't instruct, the devil
instructs for us.
And much of what our children are today
is instruction from the devil. And
because they don't know the other side
of the coin, they live by the only side
that they under stand
because you will not keep your child
forever.
You can monitor them up to probably
primary school. High school they are
gone. Do you know what they're doing in
high school? Even if you were protective
beyond high school, they're in the
university in campus. Do you even know
the house where they have rented?
I went to one house
when my nephew
I was called by the mother, please check
on so and so
is in Burubu police station. So I rushed
to Burubu
and then I they asked me
I said
rudely the officer told me
and I said
and they searched he was not there. I
called again. Did you sayu or what? Say
no they have said ru. So I have had
again to move up to ru. So I went found
him in the cells.
And I asked to speak to him and it
involved a lost laptop
and his friends were there also and I
asked the friends do you know the owner
of the laptop? They said yes.
Can I see the owner of the laptop
to a plot where students stay? One
house. I find the girl seated on the bed
is a one-bedroom house, sitting room,
kitchen, toilet, bathroom. So the girl
is seated. The sitting room only has one
bed and at the side window there is one
mattress and then I sit also on the bed
and I asked do you know this my nephew?
They all kept quiet first. The friend is
a girl and a boy and this other girl now
seated.
So I asked, "Do you know
this my nephew?" They kept quiet.
I asked again, "I'm talking to you. I'm
told you're the owner of the laptop. Do
you know my nephew?" Then the other girl
says, "We will tell you the truth. This
is your nephew's girlfriend."
Okay.
And then I said, "So if this is your
boyfriend, what happened? How did the
laptop disappear? And then the boy now
tells me, in fact, she's not supposed to
be living here. She was living in the
other house. Had another boyfriend who
kicked her out. So your nephew took her
in to help and they ended up becoming
boyfriend and what? Girlfriend. So I
stopped the whole questioning of laptop
and what and I asked, I want to know who
sleeps on this bed that I'm sitting.
And then I was told it is your nephew
and her but what about that other
mattress is for a first year who could
not afford and the parent requested if
he can find some friends to host. So my
nephew sleeps with a girl on this bed
and that mress is for um a first year
but I've seen another bedroom the other
side. Who sleeps there?
Then they kept quiet. Whose bedroom is
the other one? They say it's for us two.
These are the two boy and a girl.
So I asked, "How do you sleep?"
And I think they understood my question.
They say, "We use protection."
Shamelessly,
we use protection.
I was so disgusted.
I left the place with one question. When
your child is in compass, do you even
know where they stay? They will tell you
you you you will tell your parents rent
is 3,000
and then you go get some two, three
other friends, men and girls in it in
the mix and they rent one space where
they pay 3,000. The other money they use
it for other things. But your mother in
the village knows you have a rental
space which you will never see until you
graduate and every month we keep on
sending you rent.
The things that are happening out here I
am saying parents
you will not hold on to a child forever.
There's a time to let them what leave.
It could be in compass. It could be in
high school. If a child is not trained
well then they become vulnerable because
they have training from the other side
the other world because their world the
training was avoided intentionally
because it is taboo to talk about sex
and sexuality on the pulpit. It's taboo
for a mother and a father to address sex
and sexuality with their children. is
taboo even in school is what the African
culture believes. So when we don't teach
the devil teaches and they take that as
the only teaching and so they are
cohabiting they are getting pregnant
aborting continuing with life.
I'm asking are we available
for training up a child? The truth is we
are not. We are missing in action. Our
parents are available.
Number two, are we knowledgeable?
Today we are beast chasing career,
increasing our academic qualifications
from work straight to an evening class.
You learned in the house at 10.
acquiring more knowledge on your career
advancement
but no knowledge on how to raise our
what our children.
Number three, reliability speaks to
consistency. We are not consistent with
our children. So what you realize at the
end of the day? You have children in the
house but you have no relationship with
what? With your children. They have
things they want to share but they
cannot share because the relationship
between the two of you is so cold. It's
about pocket money is about school fees
and rent question.
So they meet their teachers and
instructors in campus who will tell them
what life is. And when you think an
innocent child, you say that they were
raised in church. And most of our
children are raised in church but they
never grew in Christ. They grew in
church but never grew in who? In Christ.
Because we thought bringing them on
Sabbath to Sabbath school to campouts to
club meetings that was raising children.
So they grew up in the church. Yes. But
they never grew up in Christ. So she
goes to campus, finds a life that she
was never introduced to and it looks
adventurous
and just like pastor said, innocent
lives that were
deceived into some party meeting.
Very innocent. And she felt she could
take care of herself, but it ended up so
badly.
She's explaining an occurrence I had
with a friend's daughter.
This one had just cleared. No, it was
form three. And in December, she went to
look for some little money. So, sorry.
Walked in a shop.
And uh this December 25th,
workmates in the shop gathered together
and said, "We have a party at night."
She also left. She's in form three at
that time. And then she says, "I don't
know. me. I woke up in the toilet and
found myself sleeping there. So they
spiked her drink.
So she comes back home.
She misses her period
innocently. The mother takes her to
hospital. She feels malaria
and she's pregnant.
They want to ask and find out you know
the man and she's saying I don't know
chances are spiked her drink ripped her
so she's in school as I go to see
Natalie in school the parents see me ask
me to see their daughter because she
insists she wants to come out of school
so I call her and And I ask her, "Mama,
why do you want to go out of school?"
She says, "I'm just tired.
I'm just tired."
That one, you know, is before the
parents knew she was pregnant cuz she
just went to school when they opened.
So when she insisted, they brought her
and then that is when she was taken to
hospital and she was pregnant. We had to
sit have a sincere discussion whether to
abort this or not. She didn't
cuz that is not the right thing to do.
That girl I think is now six or so years
old, very pretty young girl,
but something that could have been
avoided.
So when someone says, "What is this in
night life that people enjoy that I
don't know?" You know at times you could
have a child grow up in church and the
only thing they know is school, church,
house. They lack expos
exposure.
Why can't we give exposure to our
children as parents?
Must we do all dinners in the house? Why
can't we do dinner as a family out
there?
So that when I am introduced to dinner
with a stranger, it's not a new thing.
Why can't I hug my child so tight
as a father?
Say baba, come. Hey, sm
you're fine.
He's your child. The only thing they
hear from you is
Then they have an experience of the
first hug encompass
and it's a honest hug from a church
elder who is a student and she believes
this is elder one of our church there's
nothing wrong and she feels for the
first time she feels this is how a hug
feels like
and things go south.
So we can sit here and blame each other
but I would say our time parenting was
different from their time.
I think the parents today are just not
there.
very few have deliberately and
intentionally decided to be there but it
has costed them something for them to be
present
and I think that is another question
I've been asked there
that how practical is it
to I think balance career and children
or something they want the practicality
is a question I've never liked
you want us to write a book on how to
make money,
how to leave work and come and take care
of your children is a decision you make
is a choice.
It must cost you one thing
and you must be willing
to let go one but you cannot find
balance between the two.
I would say we love you.
I'm also protective of my children, but
I wouldn't want to be overprotective
because I would be raising a zombie.
With six children, I cannot work like a
donkey. There are things I've had to
trust them with, bank accounts, monies,
running the house, and I'm not worried.
When an eagle teaches the iglets to fly,
they're in the nest for some time. But
it comes a time the eaglets must learn
how to do what? To fly. If you have
watched it,
it goes with the igllets up the sky,
releases them. If you see how the iglets
are suffocating and flapping their
wings, IT'S LIKE CRYING, "MOMMY, MOMMY,
I'M FALLING." Mommy's just there
watching, flying around them, but when
they're just about to touch the ground,
it goes beneath them
and carries them
until they learn to fly. I think we have
been unable to teach our eagles to do
what? To fly. They are overdependent on
us.
And so it has stifled and chocked their
ability to think on their own.
And I can see them even right here in
church. How children, young children
control us right here in church.
A child wants to control you. It is
because that is how you have raised that
child. We are so absent that to make up
for our absence, we would want to give
anything a child wants.
Even when their school days, we don't
attend them sincerely. We are busy at
work. You only ask for a 30 minute break
to make a technical appearance for a
photo and then rush back to work. And a
child should believe you show up. You
showed up for them.
So I think much is with us parents
but I can tell you for a fact our
children are suffering.
Being a counselor, contacted every time
by young people, the conversation starts
like this. I want to tell you something
that I cannot tell my father or mother.
Why can't you tell your father and
mother we are not close?
That is what they say. They say we are
not what? We are not close.
And you cannot be close when you're
absent. You've got to be present to be
close to your child. That is when they
will tell you they are fierce. That is
when they will tell you the
expectations. That is when they will
tell you what they need. Otherwise, our
children are being raised out here by
the devil himself.
And they do not know any better. Why
would an Adventist church in campus have
elders that impregnate
fellow church members?
and notorious for every first year that
comes has someone there drops the other
one. A young girl came to my office
wretched completely.
She has not showered. There's a friend
that has brought her.
So what have you come to do pastor? I'm
in compass.
And she explains a pure life before she
came to campus. Then when I came this
guy asked me out and I accepted because
he was the first elder of the church a
student. They got into an affair. Then
she says
that is what they say.
Then we we slept together.
[snorts]
Then I says okay I understand what you
mean by vikafik.
So what is wrong right now? What is
wrong is for the years I've been there,
he's always cheated on me with other
girls. So you decided to continue. Yeah,
I decided to continue because you know
sex is not a small thing. It's not once
you sleep with someone is an is a bond
that is difficult to do what to break.
You you form soul ties
that are very difficult to break.
So even when you're told this guy has
other women, you feel like no, he has
taken away my virginity, you also want
to fight for the same man only to
realize the guy has paraded so many
women in fact currently has a first year
when she's a second year.
And then she says this, "For now I'm
not, it's not difficult for me to let
him go, but I feel dirty because these
things we even did them in the vestry in
church."
In the vest in where?
In church.
This girl has not done exams. People
have done cuts. People She has not. She
says, "I can't concentrate."
So now she's calling the boy cuz the boy
has is is has finished waiting for
graduation and the boy is not picking
his phone. I mean her phone
pastor, I have spent my money.
I have spent my help money to treat this
guy. Last time I went to bought him
shoes worth 3,500.
Hey, [screaming]
so she's crying her investments.
She's crying her her what? have
virginity.
Do your parents know? Say no. They can't
know.
They cannot know.
Let me ask a sincere question. Who is
wrong in this case? Now
is wrong.
That's why I said all factors held what?
Constant.
There comes a time
you have to do life for yourself because
it's about you.
Even if your parents didn't raise you
well, you come to a point and realize
this is about me
and you have no one to blame.
This life you cannot blame anyone even
for your poverty. You cannot blame your
background.
You can't
that you see I'm poor because I came
from a humble there's nothing called a
humble background is poor.
If you're poor you're poor
and you can't keep crying all the time
crying because see I come from a poor
background. No, you have to make the
difference.
You have to rise
and change what your parents could not
change because this world is so cold. It
does not care where you come from. This
world doesn't care you are an orphan. It
does.
The world doesn't care even for widows.
The world doesn't care that there's a
widow. There is no that is subsidized
for widows. The world is so cold.
You are your own rescue.
So there's an age you reach on this one,
this age here. You cannot even blame
your parents that didn't raise you well.
You sit AND ASK YOURSELF, WHAT DO I want
to be in the future?
Because some of us are not lucky to have
parents in church. There are children
out here. The parents don't even know
the door of a what of a child. You have
a drunkard FOR A FATHER.
AND YOU HAVE A PROSTITUTE for a mother
and they have to make it in life.
A point comes in life you sit
ask yourself very difficult questions
because you are responsible for all the
choices that you make.
I can tell you we can blame God for sin.
We can equally blame the devil for sin.
Ellen White says we are beings created
with free will.
To make a choice is a privilege.
But as you make the choice, you have the
responsibility.
You are responsible for the choices you
make. So she says you can never blame
God or Saturn, heaven or hell for the
[clears throat] choices you do what you
make. You can't. Not all of us are the
same. There are children that are even
they're total orphans
adopted.
I meet them in my office. I have
particular one
a family of six. She's also adopted.
Well educated abroad come back. Finds
jobs can't keep them. Money she doesn't
know where it goes. Every job she gets
one 2 3 months she loses. And we pray
together.
Kumbbe she lands in a family. And this
thing is difficult for me to explain.
This is now for those who understand
what happens in the realm of the spirit.
It is this home that has adopted a child
to use half her favor for the
advancement of their children.
You see, like you get into a home, you
are six brothers and then there's this
one brother who has an evil altar cuz
witchcraft is about suppressing others
for you to do what? To grow. That is
what they have done to that girl. We
prayed and I told her you will get a
job. Whatever happens to that family,
God knows. She walks into my office a
month ago says I got a job
with the Somali embassy.
Good job. But pastor,
all my siblings,
the biological children, all of them are
now jobless.
All
we are raised in different
circumstances.
I have one I am currently handling.
Adopted from babyhood.
This is sad.
That's why I'm saying all factors l
constant. Adopted from babyhood. As she
grew in this home,
went through primary school, never knew
she was adopted.
And then she says, "The home I was
living in had two houses. There was one
house we lived in. The other one I never
knew what happens there, but there's a
season family members come together.
Sisters to the mother of the house and
they meet there and no one is allowed in
that house as she grew up.
But
as she was growing up from class 5, the
man of the house would rape her.
So she asked if this is my father. You
know when you adopt a child from
babyood, they don't know. They know you
are the father. So she would ask why
would my father sleep with me? She
continued up to high school. The family
moved to the US with their children. But
anytime she closes school, the man
comes, flies in to sleep with her, then
flies out. She goes to school pregnant.
So she says she never settled through
her high school because she was always
expelled from one high school to another
because of pregnancy. She managed to
finish. When she finished, they
approached her. Every time they closed
three times, that man must fly into the
country.
So when she came to campus,
they approached her and told her,
"You're now old enough to advance your
lineage."
She didn't know what that meant until
one day she says, "I was cleaning the
house
and I noticed the bedroom of the mother,
the person I call my mother, no one is
allowed inside.
There was a fridge and a big fridge.
So she decides to go. One day she's
allowed to clean and curiosity she
decides to open the fridge.
And when she opened, she couldn't
believe it. Fetuses
are stucked inside. Because even for
her, anytime she was expelled, she says,
"The first time I was expelled, my
mother was called."
And she said, "Yuniko." Then they ended
up doing an abortion for her in the
house. And they said, "This child will
keep it in the fridge." They she asked
why. She said, "No, we will dispose it
tomorrow." And as she's there still
gazing at what is in the fridge,
the voice from the door, "What are you
doing?
there.
So what she's supposed to inherit as an
advancement of her lineage is the evil
altar of her what? Her home.
This girl
is tormented by demons every night
sleeping with her.
As we speak, the whole family, all
members died. all of them and she says
the last person who died was the mother
and still from US she could call her and
ask her you've refused to inherit the
altar so it was left with the sister of
the mother who now had to take her
daughter to inherit it now it is the
daughter tormenting this girl
so when we began to pray with her I now
receive anonymous text
let me see if you can help her haha that
is our vessel for producing children in
the world of darkness.
This girl is pregnant,
demonic,
and if you test her, it's positive and
she loses it. That is a life.
So if you have a mother and a father,
even if they don't talk to you, you're
lucky.
There are children out here that were
adopted for wrong wrong reasons. We are
still handling a case. We had to move
her from where she stays close to us
just to keep praying for this girl.
the things we see in the office here
when people come
demon possessed ones. I was speaking to
one, she seated there. I'm seated here
and she said, "I want to see you." So,
she booked an appointment. She came. So,
when she came, she she stopped at the
door of the office. Then she began
looking at at
the ceiling and then I asked, "What is
wrong?" I said no you I cannot come
close to you
I see fire. Then I knew this one is
demon possessed. So I said can I pray
for you? She said yes. Then after we had
prayed she gathered courage sat on the
seat. So I prayed again. Now tell me
what is wrong. Her mouth can't even
open.
They have held her mouth.
I pray for her again. Now speak. But she
can't look at me straight in the eye.
She's avoiding eye contact. But any
moment I ask her, why aren't you looking
at me? When she turns her her head to
look at me, I see a woman. When she
turns again and back to me, I see a man.
So I keep on seeing a woman. I keep on
seeing a man with some hairs like this.
So I said, "Hold on. I want to ask you a
question cuz you're going around. Are
you a lesbian?
And the demon just manifested.
[snorts]
So you you still talking about alcohol
going for dinner AT 6. PEOPLE ARE
SUFFERING serious things out [laughter]
here
and you're disturbing us here with what
time you should come home.
And we are still arguing with you. Ah
mom allow me 30 minutes now. What is the
difference between 9 and 9:30?
We have children out here are suffering
serious demonic attacks.
THEY HAVE NO FATHER. They have no
mother.
So I get her history and her story. She
tells me
her uncle started sleeping with her when
she was in class 4.
Anytime you hear a child complain of
molestation
and they keep quiet until they are old,
chances are they're being recruited into
the world of darkness.
Children who are struggling with
addictions, drug and substance abuse,
most of them use it to cover up, but
they're actually suffering
torments from the evil one. They are
tormented. You see, like you'd have
stress with your wife and say, "Let me
go and drink beer to forget." They use
drugs
to kill those memories.
So you you think you're doing a rehab
for your child, they keep relapsing.
They will not tell you they've been
drafted into the world of Illuminati.
They can't.
So we can't sit here to discuss when you
should go from home and come back. There
are serious things that devil is working
out in the world of darkness for the
attack of our children. My sincere and
honest advice would be abide in Christ.
Abide in who?
>> Abide in Christ. And if your parents
failed, you are old enough to practice
personal religion. You're old enough to
have a walk with God. Don't blame
anyone.
Don't.
I think our time is over. Seven more
questions remaining
which I will request the youth leader
if we could organize other sessions
so that we could
handle them. Alternatively, we can
handle one or two during our dinner
session which I don't even know up to
now where it is
but we could handle where
oh here or chuck here. Dinner is not
far. Chuck Chuck is the next door
neighbor. That is where we are. We can
handle the rest of the questions there.
Whatever will remain pending, we will
look for another afternoon on Sunday. We
come and handle them. I wish you well
and I pray that you grow to the measure
and stature of Christ himself.
Now you have to close the chapter behind
whether you are raised well or you are
not raised well. Understand you must be
responsible for every decision you make.
Let us pray.
Our heavenly father
this life is not innocent. Behind the
curtains
is a serious warfare between light and
darkness.
Ellen White says a war that would be
between two armies
of a country.
There are some things you have not
permitted us to see or know. If we did,
we will lose our minds.
We are safe under your wings. The
battles you fight for us unknown to us.
And at the end of the day, we can only
say, "I felt some shaking here and
there, but I'm okay."
Okay? Because you fought it without our
knowledge.
We're in a dark world
covered with darkness. Gross darkness.
It is true exoterically things look fine
but esoterically
it's dark it's rotten.
No one would want to behold
and by the time we find out about it
it's too late.
Permit us a perception
that goes beyond what the eyes can see.
Allow us a discernment
of spiritual things, beyond what the
physical can offer.
My Lord and Savior,
open the eyes of our understanding
that we can look at things from your own
spectacles.
Today the devil is outraged.
He's coming after the church,
coming after our children, coming after
our marriages. That is where he has
launched the hardest of attacks.
and he's reaping big, adding more and
more people to his ranks
while we are asleep,
complacent,
comfortable where we are as if nothing
is going on.
Allow us to have or cultivate a battle
sensitivity.
Teach us to be more conscious
that when the enemy launches an attack,
we can counterattack.
unfortunately even ignorant on how to
counter attack and you lament my people
perish for lack of knowledge.
May each one of us
from whichever
standpoints we are in our Christian
growth,
I pray you will reveal to us the things
that no one can ever teach us even on
this pulpit.
things that will be just one truth, but
a door, a door that opens up to a whole
world of truth that we were never
taught, led by the power of the Holy
Spirit.
We commit our young ones into your
hands.
Watch over them. Protect them from harm
and danger. I pray for a commitment.
a commitment that will have them have
the strength to detach completely from
the world and walk in the light.
I pray for our parents we will
reconsider.
You cannot compare raising a child to
any profession in this world. You can't.
Tough choice to make. Parents are
battling with it. But the reality is
the right choices are never easy. They
are always tough. But when we stand with
you, you'll always stand with us. As we
continue with our worship experience,
we still believe your presence is with
us. Prepare us for the kingdom to come.
This we have prayed in Jesus name. Amen.